Michael Lewis Collection
Michael Lewis Collection
1951-1953
Lewis, Michael, 1930-
1 half-letter box
Photographs of Michael Lewis, actor, and a single clipping
2458716
Biographical History
Michael Lewis, son of journalist Dorothy Thompson and writer Sinclair Lewis. Stage and screen actor.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Michael Lewis Collection consists mainly of photographs -- head shots and photos of Lewis in various roles ranging from Don John the Bastard ("Much Ado About Nothing" to a role in "The Virginian." There is a single clipping, a photograph of his parents.
Related Material
See also the Dorothy Thompson Papers
Subject and Genre Headings
Dance and theatre; Lewis, Sinclair, 1885-1951.; Lewis, Michael, 1930-; Thompson, Dorothy, 1893-1961.; Actors -- United States.; Clippings (information artifacts); Photographs.; Actors.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Patricia Westerfield, 28 Feb 2006.
Inventory
- Memorabilia
  - Clippings (Box 1)
- Photographs
  - Head shots (Box 1)
  - Arena Stage, Washington DC, Sep 1953 (Box 1)
    Emile Boulanger in "The Bad Angel," Depont-Dufort Sr. in "Thieves' Carnival," Brassett in "Charley's Aunt"
  - Barter Theatre of Virginia (Abingdon, VA), Jun 1951 - Dec 1953 (Box 1)
    Ezra in "Some Sweet Day," Prince of Arragon in "Merchant of Venice," Tyler Rayburn in "Light Up the Sky," Kurt Schneider in "Detective Story," "St. Peter" in "Poet in Seven," Chris Sly in "Sweet Fire," Scipio le Moyne in "The Virginian," Prince of Arragon on tour.
    Not all photos are identified and some may be missing
  - Equity Library Theatre (Chicago, IL), May 1953 (Box 1)
    Dr. Macfarland in "Hobson's Choice"
  - Port Players (Oconomowoc, WI), Jul 1953 - Sep 1953 (Box 1)
    Godfrey Pond in "The Happiest Days of Your Life," Titus Savage in "The Curious Savage," Halstead Carter in "Spring Again," Cyrus Stevens in "The Gorilla," Phillip Russell in "Affairs of State."
  - Rochester Arena Theatre (Rochester, NY), Jan 1953 - Mar 1953 (Box 1)
    Bill Walker in "Major Barbara," Don John the Bastard in "Much Ado About Nothing"
  - Unidentified (Box 1)